Visual Geometry Group (VGG)
Department of Engineering Science
University of Oxford

⊠ cxzheng@robots.ox.ac.uk

"thttps://chuanxiaz.com/

⊕ lyndonzheng

Chuanxia Zheng

Research Interests

My research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for scene understanding and synthesis. I have done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of *synthesizing a photorealistic virtual world* via generative AI.

Education

Nanyang Technological University	2017.08 – 2021.07
Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning	
Advisor: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai	
Beihang University	2014.09 – 2017.03
MA.E. in Automation Science	
Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot	2010 00 2014 07
Beijing Jiaotong University B.E. in Electronic and Information Engineering	2010.09–2014.07
Employment	
University of Oxford	2022.12-now
PostDoctoral Researcher Fellow in Computer Vision	2022.12 HOW
Research interests: 2D and 3D scene synthesis, and unsupervised learning	
Tap Mobile	2022.09 – 2022.11
AI research counselor in computer vision and machine learning group	
Research interests: 2D image generation, completion and translation	2021 00 2022 00
Monash University Postdoctoral Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology	2021.08-2022.08
Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation	
Huawei Research	2017.01-2017.06
Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab	
Research interests: face recognition and generation	
Tencent Research	2016.05–2016.09
Research Intern at Fundamental Research Center of Tencent Work on news recommendation	
Research Experience	
VinAI, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Dr. Hung Bui	2021.11-2022.08
Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression three papers accepted by NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1)	
Department of Data Science & AI, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai	2021.08 – 2022.08
Research interests: nature scene generation and completion three papers accepted by CVPR(1), ECCV(2), one paper submitted to TPAMI	
Mechanobiology Institue (MBI), NUS, Singapore, Prof. Lim Chwee Teck	2020.01 – 2021.10
Cooperator on cell nuclear generation one paper accepted by Plos one(1)	
Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann	2017.08-2021.06
Research interests: photorealistic image generation	
seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)	2014 00 2017 02
IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation	2014.09–2017.03
1600 cm americano. Scene understanding and segmentation	

Awards & Honors

NeurIPS 2022 Scholar/Travel Award		2022
NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award		2022
TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award		2021
NTU Research Scholarship		2017
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing		2014
National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best or	ne in Beijing)	2013
Hanergy Scholarship Award (Top 1%)		2012
Siemens Scholarship Award (Top 1%)		2011
Press Coverage		
Sber.ru: MoVQ — 0.1 means a lot for text-image generation Kandinsky 2.1		2023
Phys.org: Researchers unravel cell biology through artificial intelligence		2022
NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022		2022
Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng		2022
kknews, Sohu, Net Ease: Agile GAN — a new tool for creating stylized portraits		2021
Academic Services		
Journal Reviewer		
IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence	r ·	ТРАМ
International Journal of Computer Vision		IJCV
IEEE Transactions on Image Processing		TIF
IEEE Journal of Automatica Sinica		JAS
IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021)		TMN
IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology	7	Γ CSVT
Computer Vision and Image Understanding		CVIU
The Visual Computer		TVC
Neural Computing and Applications		NCAA
Conference Reviewer		
Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2020, 2021, 202	22, 2023
European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	202	20, 2022
International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2019, 202	21, 2023
International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2021, 202	22, 2023
Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	202	22, 2023
International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)		2023
International Conference on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH)	202	21, 2022
International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)		2023
International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)		2022
International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)		2022
ACM Multimedia (ACMMM)	202	21, 2022
Talks		
Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU	2	2023.04
Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2	2023.04

Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU	2022.09
Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2022.08
Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH	2022.06
Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC	2022.01
Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2019.11
Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2018.06
Teaching	
Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU	2018-2020
Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU	2018-2020
$\textbf{Teaching Assistant}, \ Engineering \ Mathematics, \ Undergraduate, \ NTU$	2018–2019
Advising	
PhD students	
Zeyu Wang, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Fengming Liu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Tianhao Wu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Minghui Hu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2022-present
Yuedong Chen, Monash University, co-supervised with Prof. Jianfei Cai	2021-present

[19] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung.

Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(1), NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)

In The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.

(ICML), 2023.
 [18] Minghui Hu, Chuanxia Zheng, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation.

Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. In The Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning

- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *Thirty-sixth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems* (NeurIPS), 2022.
- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan*, **Chuanxia Zheng***, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (*ECCV*), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.

- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision*(ICCV), pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV), 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

Preprints

- [5] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Online clustered codebook. Under reviewer.
- [4] Tianhao Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Ipo-ldm: Depth-aided 360-degree indoor rgb panorama outpainting via latent diffusion model. *Under reviewer*.
- [3] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer*.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer*.
- [1] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *Under reviewer*.